[{"question":"What is sarcomere?","a":"Part between two H-lines","b":"Part between two A-band","c":"Part between two I-bands","d":"Part between two Z-lines","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which one of the following is a skull bone?","a":"Atlas ","b":"Coracoid","c":"Arytenoid ","d":"Pterygoid","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"During muscle contraction:","a":" ATP is broken down","b":"ATP is formed","c":"GTP is broken down","d":"None of the above","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"During muscle contraction:","a":"ATP is broken down","b":"ATP is formed","c":"GTP is broken down","d":"None of the above","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which is a part of pectoral girdle?","a":"Glenoid cavity ","b":"Sternum","c":"Lium","d":"Acetabulum","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following is striped muscle but not voluntary in action?","a":"Cardiac muscle ","b":"Abdominal","c":"Shank","d":"Wrist Muscles","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following are involved in muscle contraction?","a":"Ca2+ and Mg2+","b":"Ca2+ and Na+","c":"Na+ and K+","d":"Mg2+ and K+","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Part of the body having a single pair of bones is:","a":"Pelvic girdle ","b":"Wrist","c":"External Ear ","d":"Lower Jaw","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Cardiac muscles are different from that of skeletal muscles as the former are:","a":"Striated but involuntary.","b":"Non-striated and involuntary.","c":"Smooth or unstriated.","d":"Voluntary in action.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following joint is found between sternum and the ribs in humans?","a":"Angular joint ","b":"Fibrous Joint ","c":"Cartilaginous Joint","d":"Gliding Joint","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following sets of antagonistic muscle is incorrect?","a":"Flexor -Relaxor","b":"Abductor - Adductor","c":"Pronator - Supinator","d":"Levator - Depressor","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which one yields ATP, required for muscl contraction?","a":"Myoglobin","b":"Creatine phosphate","c":"Creatinine phosphate","d":"Myosin","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Ankle joint is:","a":"Pivot joint","b":"Ball and socket joint","c":"Hinge joint","d":"Gliding joint","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following is not exclusively supplied with involuntary muscles?","a":"Muscles of iris","b":"Muscles of the ducts of gland","c":"Muscles of urethra","d":"Muscular coats of blood vessel","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"ATPase activity is found in:","a":"Mvosin filament ","b":" Actin Filament ","c":"Both (A) And (B) ","d":"None Of These","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Biceps are attached with:","a":"Radius ","b":"TIlna","c":"Femur","d":"Humerus","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Example of an imperfect joint is:","a":"Suture","b":"Pubic Symphysis","c":"Joint","d":"Ball And Socket Joint","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Example of an imperfect joint is:","a":"Suture","b":"Pubic Symphysis","c":"Elbow   Joint","d":"Ball And Socket Joint","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Elbow joint is:","a":"Ball and socket ioint","b":"Hinge joint ","c":"Suture Joint","d":"Gliding Joint","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which set clearly identify striated muscles?","a":"Cylindrical, syncytial and unbranched","b":"Spindle, unbranched and uninucleated","c":"Cylindrical, striped and nucleated","d":"Cylindrical, striped and branched","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The joint between incus and stapes is:","a":"Hinge joint ","b":"Gliding Joint","c":"Pivot Joint","d":"Ball And Socket Joint","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which is a high energy compound in muscles?","a":"Glucose","b":"Starch","c":"Glycogen","d":"Creatine Phosphate","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Muscles must have something rigid to pull against if they are to cause movement. In case of humans, the rigidity is supplied by______ ; in the case of earthworms, the rigidity comes From_____.","a":"a hydrostatic skeleton; an endoskeleton.","b":"opposing muscles; an exoskeleton.","c":"an exoskeleton; an endoskeleton.","d":"an endoskeleton; a hydrostatic skeleton.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Sutures present between various bones of skull are:","a":"Cartilaginous joints ","b":"Synovial Joints","c":"Hinge Joints","d":"Fibrous Joints","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Astragalus and calcaneum are part of:","a":"Forelimb ","b":"Hindlimb","c":"Scapula","d":"Clavicle","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The lactic acid generated during muscle contraction is converted to glycogen in:","a":"Muscle ","b":"Kidney","c":"Pancreas","d":"Liver","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Hinge joints:","a":"are synovial joints","b":"permit movement in one direction","c":"are found in knee","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"In mammals, the number of cervical vertebrae is:","a":"7","b":"9","c":"1","d":"12","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Joint between atlas and axis is:","a":"Pivot joint ","b":" Saddle Joint","c":"Angular Joint","d":"Hinge Joint","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Muscles are arranged in pairs,______.","a":"enabling them to perform opposing movements.","b":"doubling their strength.","c":"so they can take turns contracting and resting.","d":"so if one is injured, the other can take over.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The strength of contraction of an entire skeletal muscle is dependent on the:","a":"number of muscle fibres that contract simultaneously.","b":"frequency of contraction of each muscle fibre.","c":"number of active cross bridges in each muscle fibre.","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Part of the body having a single pair of bones is:","a":"Pelvic girdle ","b":"External Ear","c":"Wrist","d":"Lower Jaw","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The functional unit of contractile system of a striated muscle is:","a":"Sarcomere ","b":" Z-Band","c":"Sarcosome","d":"Myofibril","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"During muscle contraction:","a":"Size of A-bands remains the same.","b":"Size of H-zone becomes smaller.","c":"Size of I-bands decreases.","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Quadriceps and gastrocnemius muscles lie in:","a":"Legs ","b":"Hands","c":"Wrist","d":"Shoulder","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Pneumatic bones are found in:","a":"House lizard ","b":"Pigeon","c":"Flying Fish","d":"Frog's Tadpole","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Intercostal muscles occur in: ","a":"Abdomen ","b":"Thigh","c":"Ribs","d":"Diaphragm","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"find in both a skeletal muscle cell and a cardiac muscle cell?","a":"Actin filaments ","b":"Myosin Binding Sites","c":"Potassium channels that close slowly after an action potential.","d":"Large numbers of mitochondria","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Striated muscle fibres are found in:","a":"Urinary bladder ","b":"Lungs","c":"Gall Bladder ","d":"Leg Muscles","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following animal has no skeleton?","a":"Sponge ","b":"Butterfly","c":"Jelly Fish ","d":"Star Fish","hint":"","correct":"c"}]